Hello! I'm Alex. I am currently doing a postgraduate degree in Information Security. I have full-stack software development experience and I am interested in computer security and machine learning research - specifically where the two disciplines intersect. In my spare time, I like to stay fit, so running and going to the gym are things I do a lot.

</>
SKILLS

Frontend HTML CSS Sass React Gatsby

Backend SQL GraphQL REST OAuth Linux/Unix SQL Server PostgreSQL Cloud AWS Azure Docker Kubernetes DigitalOcean CloudFormation

Programming Java C#/.NET Python JavaScript TypeScript Go C++

EMPLOYMENT

Junior Software Engineer (Placement), Avco Systems Ltd

2018-07 - 2019-07

My role within the company encompassed a wide range of activities and duties, from writing code for new products in a variety of languages, testing, code review and taking a proactive role in deploying and maintaining existing software. I also helped support a B2B project that I was working on, and ensuring that requested changes were made quickly but without compromising quality.

- · Learned a lot about deploying to AWS, and using an 'infrastructure-as-code' approach to enable rapid release
- I was involved with a new project and gained valuable insight into the specification of software requirements and system architecture design
- · Took charge of updating an existing project to incorporate new important security updates and ensure that it was robust
- An early adopter of TypeScript and React (stateless components) that facilitated use in other projects to improve type safety and general software stability

Data Analyst Intern, iris Worldwide

2017-06

Understanding the vast ocean of data relating to how customers interact with brands is very important, and undertaking an internship there offered me insight into what happens 'behind the scenes'.

- Fixed issues with an important data aggregation process with Instagram/Facebook
- Used my Python skill to speed up the processing and transformation pipeline, as well as improving the existing code to make it more maintainable and documented throughout

EDUCATION

MSc Information Security, University of Surrey

2020-09 - Present

COMM058 - Architectural Thinking for Security COMM044 - Symmetric Cryptography COMM045 - Asymmetric Cryptography COMM037 - Information Security Management

BSc (Hons) Computer Science, University of Surrey

2016-09 - 2020-05

Sixth Form, Queen Mary's Grammar School

2014-09 - 2016-06

A level Computing - A A level Mathematics - B A level Physics - C AS level English Language & Literature - B

Secondary School, Cannock Chase High School

2009-09 - 2014-06

6 A*s, 3As, 2Bs including English and Maths

WRITING

Machine learning-driven detection and classification of software vulnerabilities in source code, Alex Potter, University of Surrey

2020

My undergraduate thesis about optimising ML classification of software source code to speed up code analysis and enable developers to check code for security issues.

RECOGNITION

British Informatics Olympiad - First Round, British Informatics Olympiad

2015

Fitness Current

Music Current

Version: 2021-01-22-721eb6d